justlisted.com 2015-06-18

# Real estate marketing software for prospects, client management, websites | Market Leader

### Effective Date for New Users: October 23, 2014/Effective Date for Current Users: November 7, 2014

Welcome! Protecting your privacy is really important to us. Accordingly, we at Trulia, Inc. and our affiliates (together, " **Trulia** " or " **we** " or " **us** " or " **our** ") are providing this Privacy Policy to explain our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information that we receive when you use or visit our websites or mobile apps (" **Sites** ") or our products or services (collectively, the " **Services** "). This Privacy Policy applies only to those websites (listed in the [validation page](https://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/Trulia,-Inc-/validation?rid=c8bf0c98-50c4-4a78-bd45-e5c659e5773c)), services and applications included within "Services" and doesn't apply to any third-party websites, services or applications, even if they are accessible through our Services.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy:

  * After our acquisition of Market Leader, Inc., we decided to have one, unified privacy policy for the Trulia family of companies and online properties.
  * We provide additional information on our use of online behavioral advertising and options you have around the targeting of ads to you.

### To Whom Does this Privacy Policy Apply?

This Privacy Policy applies to everyone who uses our Services, but sometimes we direct parts of it toward particular groups of users. When we do, we use the following special terminology to refer to them:

" _User_ " means anyone who uses our Services.

" _Real Estate Professional_ ," or " _REP_ ," means a User who uses our Services to promote, offer, sell or lease real estate or financial services, participate in our advertising services, or use other Services that we direct towards the professional real estate and mortgage community. A REP may be a landlord, property manager, real estate franchisor, broker or agent, home builder, mortgage professional or Subscriber.

" _Subscriber_ " means a REP who participates in our paid Services.

### What Information Do We Collect?

_We Collect Some Information From All Users_ : As part of our Services, we use various technologies such as "session" and "persistent" cookies (small data files that we transfer to your computer), web beacons (tiny image files on web pages that communicate information about the page viewer to the beacon owner), log data, and third-party analytics services to collect and analyze information about Users. This includes things like Users' search preferences, saved searches, aspects of their use of the Services, interaction with ads served through the Service and location.

We use "session" cookies to keep you logged in while you use our Services, to better understand how you interact with our Services, and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic information on our Services. We use "persistent" cookies to recognize you each time you return to our Services. For example, we create a persistent cookie that includes some basic information about you, like your most recent search and whether a REP responded to a query or request you sent using the Services. We use this persistent cookie to remember your preferences and, if you create an account, to make your user experience consistent after you register.

Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your settings or use third-party tools to refuse cookies or prompt you before accepting cookies from the websites you visit. You can also use your browser settings or other tools to delete cookies you already have. Please be aware that some parts of our Services may not work for you if you disable cookies.

Our servers automatically record information (" **Log Data** ") created by your use of the Services. Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, web pages visited, location, your mobile carrier, your computer or mobile device type, search terms and cookie information. We receive Log Data when you interact with our Services, for example, when you visit our websites, sign into our Services, or interact with our email notifications.

Our service providers and advertising networks use cookies or similar mechanisms to track and manage cookie information and your activities while you are using the Services and your activities over time and across different websites. The cookies may be used to deliver targeted ads, for example, or to analyze visitor activity. The use of cookies or similar mechanisms by our service providers and advertising networks is not covered by our privacy policy. Please see below on how to opt-out of cookie tracking.

_Information We Collect from Users with Trulia Accounts_ : Some of our Services require you to register and set up an account with us. When you create an account, we ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information like your name, email address, home or work street address and telephone number.

_Information We Collect from Users of Co-Branded Services_ : Some of our Services are co-branded and offered in conjunction with a third party. If you register or use such co-branded services, both Trulia and the third party may receive information provided by you or collected in conjunction with the co-branded services.

_Information We Collect from REPs_ : If you create a REP account with us or become a Subscriber, we will ask you to provide certain information in order to set up your account. We ask all Subscribers and REPs who set up accounts to provide their name, their employer (if applicable), a phone number and an email address. We ask real estate agents to provide their real estate license number, and we will also collect financial data like credit card information and billing addresses from Subscribers, so that we can handle billing. If you are a Subscriber, a Trulia representative may call you to verify your information.

_Information We Collect That Users Provide_ : We provide Services related to home selling, buying or renting (for example, home value estimates, moving costs, mortgage or finance costs, current home listings and neighborhood information). In order to receive these Services, we may ask you to provide certain additional information collected through our online forms, such as an approximation of your credit score, your home zip code, your eligibility for VA loans, or your desired purchase or closing date.

_Information We Collect from Users that Sign On with Facebook Connect_ : Some portions of our Services allow Users to log in using their Facebook name and password by clicking the Facebook Connect button. By using Facebook Connect, you are allowing Trulia to access some personally identifiable information in your Facebook account pursuant to the Facebook Terms of Service. Facebook Connect will pre-populate your Trulia account during the sign-up process with information from your Facebook account. Trulia will also receive your Facebook ID number during this process.

_Additional Information About You that We Obtain from Third Parties_ : We may sometimes obtain information about you from third parties and use it to provide a more tailored experience with our Services, to suggest Services that might be of interest to you, or to supplement or correct information that you have provided to us. For example, our partners may help us provide predictions of your income range and how likely you may be to purchase a home. We will share this augmented data outside of Trulia only with REPs who you choose to share information with by contacting them through the Services.

_Location Data_ : If you provide location information during the registration process or at any other time via your account settings, we will store that information and associate it with your account. In some cases we may collect and store information about where you are located, such as by converting your IP address into a rough geolocation.

If you use our mobile Sites, we will collect location data directly from your mobile device automatically if your device allows us to do so. In some circumstances, you may have to opt into sharing your location data with us. Additionally, your mobile device may provide you with choices about how and whether location data is shared with us.

### Why We Collect Information from You

Trulia provides a variety of products and services focused on the real estate and related industries. We use information we collect through the Services to:

  * Provide and improve our Services to you;
  * To manage our customer relationship with you and to provide you with customer support;
  * To process payments to us;
  * Research and analyze your use of or interest in our Services and those products and services offered by others;
  * Help you find the most relevant information for your situation by customizing our Services to optimize your experience;
  * Develop and deliver targeted advertising;
  * Analyze the effectiveness of our advertising or Services;
  * Communicate with you via email, telephone, mobile, text (SMS), postal services and websites and update you with residential real estate and mortgage-related news and information or to tell you about products or services that may be of interest to you, if you allow us to do so;
  * Put you in touch with the right people to sell, buy, rent, or research residential real estate, obtain a mortgage, and to optimize the information we share with those parties to initiate a productive and efficient relationship.
  * Verify your eligibility and deliver prizes in connection with promotions, contests and sweepstakes;
  * Manage our businesses; and
  * Perform the functions described to you at the time of collection.

### How We Share Your Information

_Personally Identifiable Information_ : We may engage third party service providers to work with us to administer, provide and improve the Services, and these third party service providers have access to Users' personally identifiable information only to perform these services for us. Otherwise, we will only share your personally identifiable information at your direction (for example, when you request to contact a REP using our Services) and according to this Privacy Policy.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information_ : In order to provide and improve our Services and to share relevant ads with you, we use and disclose to our service providers and advertising and analytics partners non-personally identifiable information that we collect, including cookie data and Log Data. We also share anonymous profiles of users who view a property with REPs, but when we do this we will not re-identify these anonymous profiles by combining them with personally identifiable information.

_Direct Contact with a REP_ : If you send an inquiry to an REP, use any other contact forms available through the Services or call a REP, we may share personally identifiable information that you share with us and information about your use of our Services with the party you wanted to contact. This may include data you input such as home search criteria, saved searches, the web pages or information you view through the Services, activity alerts or Log Data that we collect as you use the Services. One of the Services we offer is software to assist REPs collect and manage leads, and the information we provide to a REP you wish to contact may be provided to and stored in this software. REPs that you have chosen to contact may receive subsequent information collected by us about your use of the Services, including Log Data. If a REP wants to contact you based on our anonymized profile of you, we will contact you first to see if we can make that connection.

_Referrals_ : If you choose to use our referral service to tell someone else about our Services, we will ask you for that person's name and email address. We will automatically send this person a one-time email inviting him or her to visit our Sites or use our Services. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. The person you refer may contact us at [customerservice@trulia.com](mailto:customerservice@trulia.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

_Facebook Custom Audiences and Promotions_ : If you have not opted out of email communications with us, we will use your email address (and Facebook ID, if we have collected it) to promote Trulia content to you via Facebook's Custom Audiences feature and other Facebook advertising or promotional tools. The Custom Audiences feature allows us to reach out to our users via Facebook if those users have already shared their email addresses or Facebook IDs with us. If you do not want to receive promotions as part of our Custom Audiences campaigns, unsubscribe from our email list via one of the emails you receive from us, and we will remove you from our Custom Audiences list within 7 days.

_Social Network Sharing_ : When you use any social network sharing function we include with the Services (for example, sharing on Facebook), your sharing activity will be processed through a third party's site or service. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable these feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. These third parties' privacy policies, not ours, govern the collection and use of the information collected on those sites or networks.

_User-Generated Content (UGC)_ : Some parts of our Services allow Users to submit and view UGC. UGC includes such things as posting a question, an answer or a blog post. When you post UGC, other Users will be able to see certain information about you, such as your username or handle. You should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit in UGC provided by you can be read, collected, distributed or used by other Users and could be used by third parties to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to include in the UGC you provide through the Services. To request removal of your personal information from any of our blogs, you may contact us at [customerservice@trulia.com](mailto:customerservice@trulia.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

_Testimonials_ : We may display personal testimonials from users on our Site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your name along with your testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [customerservice@trulia.com](mailto:customerservice@trulia.com).

_Website Third-Party Ad Platforms_ : We use third-party ad platforms (" **Ad Platforms** ") to deliver ads to you both on our Services and on our behalf on third-party websites. Ad Platforms may collect and use non-personally identifiable information about your visits to and interactions with both our Services and third-party websites. They may compile information over time about the types of pages, content and ads you (or others who are using your computer) visit or view. They may do so by placing cookies or similar mechanisms on your browser. We do not have access to or control over those cookies or other mechanisms. Using the information they collect, Ad Platforms may display targeted ads on our Services or on third-party websites that may be of greater interest to you. The use of these mechanisms used by Ad Platforms is subject to those companies' privacy policies, not ours.

If you would like more information about these Ad Platforms' practices or to opt out of Ad Platforms using this information to provide targeted ads, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp> or [http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/?type=trulia&pid=trulia01&aid=trulia01](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/?type=trulia&pid=trulia01&aid=trulia01). Please note that if you choose to opt out using the provided links, you will be opted out of receiving targeted ads from business members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) that you select. If you do opt out, you may continue to see or receive ads on our Services or ads for services on third-party websites; however, these ads may not be as relevant to you. Please note that this opt-out mechanism works by placing a cookie on your browser, so if you delete your browser's cookies or use a different browser to visit our Services, your selected NAI members will not receive your opt-out preference and you will need to opt out again. Please also note that while certain browsers include "do not track" or similar settings, to opt out of targeted ads you should utilize the NAI opt-out mechanism identified above as our Services are not configured to respond to these settings.

_Protecting Ourselves and Our Users_ : We may release personally identifiable information when we believe that doing so is appropriate to comply with applicable laws such as to comply with a subpoena, regulations or legal requests; to enforce or apply our policies and guidelines; to initiate, render, bill, and collect amounts owed to us; to protect our rights or property; to protect the safety of our Users; to address fraud, security or technical issues; to prevent or stop activity that we consider to be illegal or unethical; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records without delay.

### General Matters

_Trulia Communications_ : You may unsubscribe at any time from receiving non-Service related communications from Trulia through your account settings or through the instructions included in the communication. You can also contact us at [customerservice@trulia.com](mailto:customerservice@trulia.com). For Service related emails, if you no longer wish to receive these you must cancel your account.

_Opting out of Push Notifications_ : You may opt out of receiving push notifications from Trulia's mobile apps on your mobile device by adjusting the settings of your mobile device. For some older mobile operating systems, you may have to uninstall our mobile app in order to stop receiving push notifications from that mobile app.

_Accessing, Modifying and Deleting Your Personally Identifiable Information_ : You can access and modify the personally identifiable information associated with your account by contacting us at [customerservice@trulia.com](mailto:customerservice@trulia.com) or by postal mail at the address listed below. If you want us to delete your personally identifiable information and your account, please contact us at [customerservice@trulia.com](mailto:customerservice@trulia.com) or at 888-466-3501. We'll take steps to delete your information as soon as is practicable, but some information may remain in archived/backup copies for our records or as otherwise required by law.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. In addition, we will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

_Children_ : The Services are not directed to children under 13, and we do not knowingly collect or store any personally identifiable information about persons under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected personally identifiable information of a child under 13, we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as practicable.

_Third-Party Websites_ : Our Services may contain links to other websites and services. Any information that you provide on or to a third-party website or service is provided directly to the owner of the website or service and is subject to that party's privacy policy. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites or services, and we're not responsible for the content, privacy or security practices and policies of those websites or services. To protect your information we recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of other websites and services that you access.

_Sale/Merger_ : Information about our Users is a business asset of Trulia. Consequently, information about our Users, including personally identifiable information, may be disclosed as part of any merger or acquisition involving Trulia, the creation of a separate business to provide some or all the Services, the sale or pledge of Trulia's assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership. If Trulia is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sales of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership that affects uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

_Security_ : We use commercially reasonable security measures to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. For example, when you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer (SSL) technology. Please be aware, however, that no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing information is completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot absolutely guarantee the protection of any information shared with us.

_Privacy Policy Changes_ : We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make material changes to our Privacy Policy, we will notify you by prominently posting the revised Privacy Policy (including the revision date) or by sending you an electronic notification of the revised Privacy Policy, prior to the change becoming effective.

_Contacting Us_ : If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
Trulia, Inc. 116 New Montgomery Street, Suite 300, San Francisco, California 94105  
[customerservice@trulia.com](mailto:customerservice@trulia.com).

### _TRUSTe:_

Trulia has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through these websites: [http://www.trulia.com](http://www.trulia.com/), [http://activerain.trulia.com](http://activerain.trulia.com/), [http://marketleader.com](http://marketleader.com/), [http://www.housevalues.com](http://www.housevalues.com/), [http://www.justlisted.com](http://www.justlisted.com/), [http://www.realestate.com](http://www.realestate.com/) and our mobile apps.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.
